 <course>
        <title>Assessing Mental Capacity Certification</title>
        <link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/assessing-mental-capacity-certification/</link>
        <CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Assessing-Mental-Capacity.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
        <location>Online</location>
        <duration>1.75</duration>
        <qualification>Assessing Mental Capacity Certification</qualification>
        <CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
        <ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
        <compatibility>All major browsers and devices</compatibility>
        <CourseCategory>Health & Social Care</CourseCategory>
        <CourseDescription><h4>Assessing Mental Capacity</h4> The Mental Capacity Act 2005 was formulated with a view to providing clear guidelines regarding assessing the mental capacity of an individual. Lack of mental capacity can lead to loss of freedom, and others may make decisions for you. This is often a transitional point in the life of any individual. This makes it all the more important that mental capacity must be evaluated using the correct techniques and methods. It’s important to assess an individual’s mental capacity correctly, and the conclusion should not be based on the individual’s age, appearance or disabilities, if any. <h4>What You Will Learn in This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>Why there are concerns regarding assessing mental capacity</li> <li>The relationship between mental capacity and decision-making</li> <li>An overview of the Mental Capacity Act (MCA) and how it underlies the principles of mental capacity assessment </li> <li>The two-stage assessment test and the five principles of the MCA</li> <liHow to use the CMSL principle for mental capacity assessment </li> <li>Who can assess an individual’s mental capacity </li> <li>How mental capacity is time and item specific, and how it can fluctuate </li> </ul> <h4>The Benefits of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>You will be able to appreciate the relevance of the MCA in mental capacity assessment </li> <li>You will learn how to avoid the common pitfalls, such as presumptions or prejudice when assessing mental capacity </li> <li>You will be able to make a much fairer, more reliable and unbiased assessment of mental capacity </li> <li>You will learn to differentiate between unwise decisions and lack of mental capacity and give the individual the benefit of the doubt </li> </ul> The outcome of a mental capacity assessment can change the course of an individual’s life by depriving them of their freedom. Therefore, it’s extremely important that the assessment process is reliable and as accurate as possible. </CourseDescription>
</course>

<course>
<title>Evaluating a Marketing Plan Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/evaluating-a-marketing-plan-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Evaluating-a-Marketing-Plan.png</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>Evaluating a Marketing Plan Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Sales/Marketing</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Evaluating a Marketing Plan</h4> Learning how to evaluate your marketing plan is absolutely vital to ensure the strength of your brand and the effectiveness of your marketing efforts. No matter your business size or nature, your success is directly linked to constantly evaluating your marketing plans. This course provides a comprehensive guide to evaluating your marketing plan by providing you with a comprehensive marketing plan checklist and brand evaluation guide to make sure you include every necessary element. From how to use customer feedback to effectively evaluate your brand image and marketing plan, to the science of specifically evaluating your digital marketing campaigns, this course covers everything you ever need to know about evaluating your marketing plan. <h4>You Will Learn</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>How to use a checklist to ensure a complete and effective marketing plan</li> <li>How to evaluate your entire brand and include it in your marketing plan</li> <li>The different methods of gathering and using customer feedback to evaluate your marketing plan</li> <li>The science of specifically evaluating your digital marketing plan</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <liYou will increase sales and revenue by improving your marketing plan</li> <li>You will improve your digital footprint and maximise site and page visits and engagement</li> <li>You will connect with your customers and gain their trust and loyalty</li> <li>You will increase your customer base and attract new business opportunities</li> </ul></CourseDescription>
        </course>

        <course>
<title>Developing a Career Strategy Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/developing-a-career-strategy-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/shutterstock_277048049-1.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>Developing a Career Strategy Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Professional Development</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Developing a Career Strategy Certification</h4> Learning how to develop a career strategy is absolutely essential to improving your overall employability, whether you’re currently working and looking to improve your position or are starting out on a new career path. This course provides a comprehensive guide to developing the right career strategy for you, including the science of self-auditing, defining your strengths and weaknesses, and finding out what motivates you. From how to gain a competitive edge to improve employability, to furthering your education and making the right connections, this course covers everything you need to know about every aspect of developing a successful career strategy. <h4>You Will Learn</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>How to audit yourself and establish your strengths and weaknesses <li>How to define your motivations and use them to find the ideal strategy <li>The science of gaining a competitive edge to improve career prospects <li>How to improve your personal skill sets and education and find the right connections</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>You will reach the career goals you’ve always dreamed of</li> <li>You will dramatically improve your employability and job prospects</li> <li>You will find the right career for your specific skills and needs</li> <li>You will improve your skill sets and connections in your chosen industry</li> </ul> </CourseDescription>
</course>

<course>
<title>Developing and Implementing New Admin Systems Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/developing-and-implementing-new-admin-systems-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Developing-Admin-Systems-1024x530.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>Developing and Implementing New Admin Systems Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Business</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Developing and Implementing New Admin Systems Certification</h4> Learning how to develop and implement new admin systems is absolutely essential for anybody looking to establish a solid and effective admin process, whether you’re just starting out or looking to make a much-needed change within your company. This course provides a comprehensive guide to developing new admin systems through a detailed needs analysis, securing team buy-in and finding the perfect structure for your needs. We also cover the science of implementation through effective training and analytics to ensure growth and constant development. From development to implementation as well as the empathy and support required for the staff involved, this course covers everything you need to know about successfully developing and implementing new admin systems. <h4>You Will Learn</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>How to perform a needs analysis during the development of a new system</li> <li>How to secure team buy-in through empathy and communication <li>How to structure your new admin systems</li> <li>Successfully implementing new systems through training and analytics</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>You will facilitate a successful transition to new and more productive admin systems</li> <li>You will dramatically improve your relationships with team members</li> <li>You will achieve and surpass departmental and company goals</li> <li>You will ensure continued growth and improvement within your department and company</li> </ul></CourseDescription>
</course>


<course>
<title>LGBTQ Awareness Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/lgbtq-awareness-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/shutterstock_1182203581-1-1.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>2.5</duration>
<qualification>LGBTQ Awareness Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Personal Development</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>LGBTQ Awareness</h4> It’s a matter of concern that, even though it’s the twenty-first century, people are still being discriminated against based on their sexual preferences, gender identity, way of dressing and for generally being who they are. It’s high time we understood the problems faced by the LGBTQ community and do our bit to help make our society inclusive and accepting of their needs. LGBTQ members have long since faced harassment, discrimination, persecution and bullying. This course on LGBTQ awareness helps highlight members of this community’s needs, challenges and issues. <h2>What You Will Learn:</h2> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>What the acronym ‘LGBTQ’ stands for and the differences between the various LGBTQ members, based on their sexual orientation and gender preferences <li> <li>Insights into the common challenges faced by LGBTQ members in their daily lives, including parenting, relationships, discrimination in public places, harassment in workplaces and housing<li> <li>How schools and other educational institutions can render staff and students sensitive to be more accepting of members of the LGBTQ community and how parents can help their LGBTQ children develop confidence and self-esteem<li> <li>About laws, acts and other government initiatives in the UK that have decriminalised homosexuality over the years <li> </ul> <h2>How You Can Benefit from This Course: </h2> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Learning about LGBTQ rights helps you become more empathetic towards and conscious of equality issues</li> <li>As an employer, parent, landlord, sibling or peer of an LGBTQ individual, you can become sensitive to their needs</li> <li>You can give and receive support from LGBTQ individuals and create flourishing educational or office environments</li> <li>You can develop individual as well as community relationships, and help LGBTQ members to integrate within their neighbourhoods and among their colleagues and family members </li> <li>Most importantly, you can educate others about LGBTQ needs, challenges and requirements and spread awareness in your community and beyond. </li> </CourseDescription>
</course>

<course>
<title>The Office Layout Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/the-office-layout-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/the-office-layout.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>The Office Layout Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Business</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>The Office Layout Certification</h4> Employees work better and more efficiently when their workspaces are well laid out. On the other hand, offices that are cluttered or chaotic tend to promote similar working environments. This principle extends beyond the workstation into how the office itself is organised. A well planned office leads to greater productivity with fewer interruptions and less time wasted each day. As a result, it is well worth your time to learn more about how to plan for the perfect office for your company’s needs. This course gives you detailed information about how to properly plan your office layout. We begin by talking about the layout of an office in general terms. Next, we move on to talk about the individual considerations you need to remember when planning your next office layout. We also review the principles of office layout, giving you more information you can use to properly plan your own. Finally, we talk about factors that may affect your own office layout plan. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>The objectives you should keep in mind when thinking about your office’s floor plan</li> <li>The benefits of paying attention to office layout</li> <li>The individual factors that go into creating a well-organised office</li> <li>What the principles of office layout are</li> <li>The factors that go into how you should lay out your office</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Learning how to create a workspace that is functional as well as attractive</li> <li>Understanding how an office layout can have such an impact on employees</li> <li>Understanding why you should think about the physical location of the building as well as how it is laid out inside</li> <li>Learning how to create a workspace that is comfortable as well as efficient for each one of your employees</li> <li>Learning how to consider your company’s needs in light of the available space when planning out an office</li> </CourseDescription>
</course>

<course>
<title>The HMT Sanctions List Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/the-hmt-sanctions-list-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/hmt-sanctions-list.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>The HMT Sanctions List Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility> All modern browsers and devices</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Business</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>THE HMT SANCTIONS LIST & CUSTOMER IDENTIFICATION </h4> HM Treasury maintains comprehensive records of all persons and entities currently subject to sanctions. This means that they face financial restrictions, usually on the basis of their links with terrorist activity or human rights abuse. If you run a business, you need to make sure that you do not handle money or assets owned by sanctioned parties, or enter into an arrangement whereby you grant them access to funds. To do so is a criminal offence. In this course, you will learn how financial sanctions work and how to meet your duties under the law. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>How financial sanctions work and the purpose and scope of the UK financial sanctions regime</li> <li>The scope and purpose of the Consolidated List and the UK Investment Ban List</li> <li>The parties responsible for maintaining these lists and how to use target and name matches to ensure that you do not engage in any transactions with individuals and entities named on the list</li> <li>How to verify customers’ identity, and the information you should collect when undertaking transactions </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>If you are a business owner, you will benefit from learning how to avoid conducting business with sanctioned parties</li> <li>If you are responsible for financial transactions as part of your job, you will benefit from learning how to verify a customer’s identity and check whether they are currently facing sanctions</li> <li>If you work in the financial sector, this course will provide you with a good introduction to sanctions</li> <li>If you work in the public sector, you may benefit from furthering your understanding of how the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), the Treasury and other bodies work together to combat crime</li> </ul> </CourseDescription>
</course>

<course>
<title>Termination of Employment Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/termination-of-employment-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/employment-termination-2-1024x530.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>2.5</duration>
<qualification>Termination of Employment Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Human Resources</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Termination of Employment Certification</h4> Terminating employment is an unfortunate part of any manager’s job. While you may strive to only recruit the best staff, the reality is that not everyone is a good fit for your company or its needs. After you go through disciplinary measures and put staff through coaching, there is a point where you simply need to move on. This is a very difficult task job, one that many managers actively avoid, which can put a strain on the rest of the office. Learning about the legal and practical aspects of employee termination can help make the process easier. This course goes into detail about each aspect of employee termination. It begins by giving you a brief overview of the legal aspects that you need to keep in mind, when considering termination of employment. Next, it covers the financial implications of dismissing an employee, helping you understand the costs involved. The level of involvement that your human resources department should have is also discussed in detail. Finally, we review the more practical aspects of termination of employment, giving you the tools that you need, in order to have that conversation. <h4>You will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>The reasons for fair dismissal</li> <li>Information regarding required notice periods, including statutory and contractual ones</li> <li>The steps that your human resources department needs to take, before you can terminate employment</li> <li>Why there is paperwork required, and what you should prepare before your meeting</li> <li>How to tell a staff member that they have been dismissed</li> <li>Who should be with you in that meeting</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of taking this Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li style="list-style-type: none"> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Understanding the difference between fair and unfair dismissal</li> <li>Learning what constructive dismissal is, so you can avoid it, where possible</li> <li>Understanding why you may wish to offer dismissed employees extra pay or extended benefits</li> <li>When you should contact security, in order to escort a dismissed employee off the premises</li> <li>How to inform the remaining staff of the change in personnel</li> </ul> </li> </ul> </ul</CourseDescription>
        </course>


        <course>
<title>Instagram Marketing Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/instagram-marketing-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/insta-marketing-1024x530.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>2.5</duration>
<qualification>Instagram Marketing Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Sales/Marketing</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Instagram Marketing Certification</h4> The world of marketing changed exponentially with the introduction of social media. Not only did social media platforms allow for a major expansion in marketing demographic outreach, but it introduced an affordable avenue for businesses and companies to market their brand. Since its inception in 2010, Instagram rapidly became a sought-after platform for marketing. As with any form of marketing, Instagram marketing requires research, legwork and a budget. However, the potential to reach the masses is far greater than with any other platform for product marketing, albeit print, digital format or social media. In this Instagram Marketing course, we will look at the brief history of Instagram to gain a better understanding of how the platform works. In addition, we will learn how to effectively use Instagram as a means of domestic and global brand outreach to maximise the potential for success. If used effectively, Instagram marketing may be the only form of marketing that is required for a brand. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>The history of Instagram</li> <li>The role that Instagram marketing plays</li> <li>The formula for Instagram’s success</li> <li>Defining business goals</li> <li>Setting marketing objectives</li> <li>How to create a content strategy</li> <li>How to define your target market on Instagram</li> <li>Instagram marketing challenges</li> <li>How to take advantage of Instagram tools</li> </ul> In general, marketing requires a good bit of research. It is important to clearly identify a brand and to market the product/service to the right demographic. Although Instagram is a social media platform, it is not exempt from the rules of efficient marketing. Therefore, to be a successful Instagram marketer or to make sure that the right form of marketing is used for a business, communities and users need to be identified. The latter is particularly important, as it is estimated that 95 million photos and videos are shared via Instagram every day. Therefore, to ensure that a brand is not lost within the sea of many brands and business, the correct target audience needs to be identified.</CourseDescription>
</course>

<course>
<title>Excel Macros Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/excel-macros-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/excel-macros-1024x530.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>2.5</duration>
<qualification>Excel Macros Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Computing/Technology</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Excel Macros Certification</h4> Learning about Excel macros is essential to anyone who uses Excel at home or work. Whether you’re looking to increase your general Excel knowledge or improve your skills in the workplace, this course covers everything you need. This course provides a comprehensive guide to Excel macros, including the references to use, and how to record and save macros. From professional tips and advice to in-depth macro categories and actual formulas you can immediately apply, this course covers everything you need to know about every element of Excel macros. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>A comprehensive definition of Excel macros and how they work <li>How to reference and record macros</li> <li>How to run, name and save macros</li> <li>Professional tips and expert advice</li> <li>Macro categories and practical coding</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>You will save time and increase productivity</li> <li>You will be able to interpret data faster and more effectively</li> <li>You will learn basic VBA coding and how to make it work for you</li> <li>You will be able to automate and optimise essential data</li> <li>You will understand the security risks associated with macros</li> </ul> </CourseDescription>
</course>


<course>
<title>Building Your Confidence and Self-Esteem Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/building-your-confidence-and-self-esteem-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/confidence-1-1024x530.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>Building Your Confidence and Self-Esteem Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Personal Development</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Building Your Confidence & Self-Esteem Certification</h4> Lots of people suffer from poor confidence and low self-esteem. If you have a negative self-image, your quality of life and relationships will suffer. Low self-esteem is also implicated in depression and anxiety, both of which can have long-lasting and serious consequences. Fortunately, you can learn to appreciate yourself and feel more confident and accepting of both your strengths and weaknesses. This course will give you practical strategies that emphasise self-acceptance and self-compassion. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>Why it is important to tackle low confidence and self-esteem</li> <li>Why you need to challenge underlying negative beliefs about yourself</li> <li>How to become more assertive and stand up for your own needs</li> <li>Why goals and challenges can help you overcome low self-esteem</li> <li>How to seek professional help if you need further assistance</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits Of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Overcoming low self-esteem and boosting your confidence will improve your general wellbeing at home and work</li> <li>If you are interested in psychopathology, this course will give you an insight into a common mental health issue</li> <li>If you support someone with low self-esteem, this course will help you understand their experiences</li> <li>If you work with service users with mental health diagnoses, this course will help you support them to build a healthier self-image</li> </ul> Please note: This course contains public sector information licensed under the Open Government Licence v3.0. </ul></CourseDescription>
        </course>


        <course>
<title>Java Certification Level 1</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/level-1-java-certification-level-1/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/java.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>3</duration>
<qualification>Java Certification Level 1</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major browsers and devices</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Computing/Technology</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4> Java Certification Level 1 </h4> Physiological studies have shown that learning to speak two or more languages can greatly benefit the cognitive process. Not only can communication expand exponentially when learning a new language, but it greatly improves the brain’s functionality. Interestingly, learning different computer languages can also provide amazing benefits. These benefits are not just mental, but are also a useful application in everyday life. Smartphones, parking key fobs, security badges and using a device to unlock a car door are some of the daily items that have been programmed to perform in a certain way. Understanding how to program, can be an amazing asset and while there are many different languages, none is quite as easy to learn as Java. Java was created with efficiency and uniformity in mind. The goal was to create a program with greater capabilities than C/C++ but with more simplicity. In this Java Programming for Beginners course you will learn the basics of programming using the Java language as well as many of the benefits that will pave the way for efficient programming. <h4>What you will learn in this course:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>How to set up a computer for Java programming and learn about pre-installed programs</li> <li>Learn about the ‘modulus operator’ and what it means</li> <li>How to identify a comment line and what the purpose of a comment is in a program</li> <li>Learn about the length method</li> <li>Learn about data structures</li> <li>Learn about class-object relationship and start learning about object-oriented programming in Java</li> Learn about Booleans and what purpose they serve</li> </ul> <h4>The benefits of this course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Learning the most commonly used computer language</li> <li>Knowing Java can increase professional opportunities as a programmer or software engineer. Java programmers are in high demand and are among the highest paid in the industry</li> <li>Java has a very in-depth API and can be used to implement other kinds of software</li> <li>It will make you a better developer with its rich IDEs (Integrated Development Environment) providing suggestions and notifying of errors</li> <li>Java will help you understand more complex programming concepts</li> </ul> </CourseDescription>
        </course>


<course>
<title>Rabbit Care Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/rabbit-care-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/rabbit-care.png</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>1.25</duration>
<qualification>Rabbit Care Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Business, Hobbies & Lifestyle</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Rabbit Care </h4> Caring for rabbits can be very rewarding, but it is a dramatically different experience than looking after cats or dogs. Rabbits have specific dietary, health and environmental needs. It is important that anyone responsible for their care knows how to meet those requirements. Doing so can lead to a long and happy life for your furry friend. This course goes over everything you need to know about providing adequate rabbit care, split across two modules. The first talks about the rabbit care in general, including a discussion of common rabbit breeds those engaged in animal welfare may encounter. An overview of the environmental needs of rabbits is also included. The second module dives into healthcare, talking about grooming and behavioural habits while also reviewing major ailments you should be aware of. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>Specific strategies you can employ to provide the rabbits in your care with an enriched environment</li> <li>How often toys must be cycled out to continue enriching your rabbit’s playtime</li> <li>The specific foods rabbits can eat on a daily basis</li> <li>The specific foods you should never feed a rabbit <li>The reasons why hay is such an important part of your rabbit’s habitat as well as diet</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Learn the benefits of getting involved with your rabbit’s grooming schedule, as well as a few tips on how to improve the bonding experience</li> <li>Learn about the difference in popular domestic rabbit breeds, to help you better choose a pet suitable for your lifestyle</li> <li>If you work in animal care, learn more about the specific health challenges facing rabbits and how you can spot the signs earlier</li> <li>If you work in pet sales, learn what kinds of conditions are required to ensure that rabbits in your care thrive before being placed in their forever homes</li> <li>If you are a prospective pet owner, learn everything you need to prepare your home for your rabbit’s arrival</li> </ul></CourseDescription>
</course>



<course>
<title>Self-harm Awareness Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/self-harm-awareness-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Self-Harm.png</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>Self-harm Awareness Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Health & Social Care</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Self-harm Awareness Certification</h4> Self-harm involves people inflicting injury on their bodies to reduce different kinds of emotional pain or to experience a certain euphoric feeling. Whatever the reasons for self-harm, they do not make sense to people who do not have this issue. Self-harm affects many people worldwide and continues to do so. The condition often points to an underlying mental illness or disorder. Therefore, it becomes important to create awareness about this condition, so that sufferers can seek help or get treatment. This course first defines self-harm and states its many forms. We then state various causes of self-harm and the signs and symptoms to look out for in those people who are suspected to have this issue. Next, we explain why people tend to engage in this painful practice that only causes them more harm. The course covers different treatment options available for self-harm and how they can help sufferers overcome the issue. Several distraction techniques that patients can adopt to help them stop self-harm, are also covered. A few myths around self-harm are also given. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>What self-harm is and what it is not</li> <li>Various synonyms used for self-harm</li> <li>Various forms of self-harm</li> <li>Causes and signs and symptoms of self-harm</li> <li>Why people engage in self-harm</li> <li>Treatment options available for self-harm</li> <li>How psychotherapy helps overcome self-harm</li> <li>Distraction techniques to help stop self-harm</li> <li>Myths around self-harm</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> Taking this course will help you: <li>Learn everything you need to know about self-harm</li> <li>Determine if you or a loved one are engaging in self-harm</li> <li>Find out about the treatment options available for self-harm</li> <li>Gain awareness on self-harm among your peers</li> <li>Decide whether you want to take a more advanced course to help those engaging in self-harm</li> <li>Understand why people inflict injury on their bodies</li> <li>Differentiate between facts and myths around self-harm</li> </CourseDescription>
</course>

<course>
<title>Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages (TESOL) Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/teaching-english-to-speakers-of-other-languages-tesol-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/TESOL.png</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>0.75</duration>
<qualification>Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages (TESOL) Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Education</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Teaching English as a Second Language (TESOL)</h4> If you are passionate about the English language and enjoy sharing your knowledge with others, teaching may be the perfect career choice for you. In particular, you may excel at teaching English as a second language to children and adults. While you do not need a specialised degree in English to pursue jobs in this field, it is a good idea to have some formal training. This course gives you an overview of teaching English as a second language, focusing on TESOL training to keep your career options open. Our course begins by talking about the various acronyms you may encounter when looking into your options for teaching English as a second language. We conclude by giving you practical tips and strategies you can use to make your lessons more engaging for students of all ages. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>The importance of using authentic materials in your lessons and how to select the most relevant ones</li> <li>More about the three main methods used to teach English to non-native speakers</li> <li>What a learner-based approach to lesson planning is and why it is important</li> <li>The importance of context when introducing new words or concepts to students</li> <li>How to successfully introduce vocabulary words to students of all ages</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Learn about the difference between TESOL, TEFL and CELTA training</li> <li>Understand what kind of supportive materials you should incorporate into your lessons</li> <li>Learn more about what is involved in teaching English to foreign-language speakers, which can help guide career decisions for students uncertain about post-secondary training</li> <li>If you are a teacher, learn more about the strategies others recommend using when educating ESL students</li> <li>If you have an ESL student in your life, learn more about how they are learning English so you can help support them at home</li> </CourseDescription>
</course>



<course>
<title>Introduction to Kennel and Cattery Management Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/introduction-to-kennel-and-cattery-management-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/shutterstock_534245917-1-1.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>1.25</duration>
<qualification>Introduction to Kennel and Cattery Management Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility>All major devices and browsers</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Business, Hobbies & Lifestyle</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Introduction to Kennel and Cattery Management Certification</h4> For an animal lover, there is no better way to earn a living than spending it with the critters you adore. This makes kennel and cattery management a very attractive career choice for so many across the UK. Having a solid understanding of both the business aspect of running a business as well as health and hygiene topics will give you the perfect start to your new career. Training in this area is something you can use throughout your life. This course tells you what you need to know about kennel and cattery management, dividing the information across two modules. The first reviews the business side of things, covering your role at the kennel or cattery and introducing you to the various types of facilities you may encounter. Our second module covers the animal health and hygiene topics you need to be familiar with in order to properly look after the animals in your care. </ul> <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>The specific tasks kennel and cattery managers are responsible for</li> <li>Information about commercial or boarding kennels or catteries</li> <li>The difference between a breeding kennel and a hobby kennel</li> <li>Information about the three main pieces of legislation you need to be familiar with</li> <li>How to comply with your local authority’s record keeping requirements</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking This Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>For those thinking about a career in animal care, learn more about what you can expect from management</li> <li>If you currently work with animals, gain additional skills and knowledge you can use to ask for a promotion or raise</li> <li>If you are a pet owner, learn more about how the kennels and catteries you bring your pets to are run</li> <li>Volunteers at kennels and catteries can learn more about accepting increased responsibilities</li> <li>If you are thinking about breeding cats or dogs, learn more about how to keep the animals safe and well cared for</li> </ul></CourseDescription>
        </course>

    <course>
<title>Nursery Assistant Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/nursery-assistant-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/nursery-assistant-1024x530.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>2.5</duration>
<qualification>Nursery Assistant Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility> All modern browsers and devices</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Education</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Nursery Assistant Certification</h4> Working with children is one of the most rewarding careers a person can have. There are many ways you can become professionally involved in a child’s education. One such position is working as a nursery assistant. These individuals are responsible for working with babies and toddlers. Part of your job may include playing with the children in your care, developing lesson plans and communicating with parents and carers about their children. You can enter this field in many different ways, with a variety of qualifications being available to you, depending on your work history, education and life experience. This course goes into detail about working as a nursery assistant to give you all the information you need to enable you to pursue a fantastic career in this growing field. We begin by giving you a brief introduction to the position, including a discussion of the required skills and anticipated salary levels. We then talk about the Early Years Foundation Stage curriculum, which you must follow when coming up with lesson plans for the children in your care. Next, we review the developmental milestones that the children in your care should be expected to meet. Finally, we talk about the importance of play when developing learning programmes. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> </li>The skills and qualifications you need to successfully obtain employment as a nursery assistant</li> </li>What the prime areas of learning are</li> </li>What the specific areas of learning are</li> </li>Which milestones you should be on the lookout for at each age, from birth to age five</li> </li>The six types of play you should encourage children in your care to engage in</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking this Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>Understanding more about this highly rewarding career</li> <li>Learning how you can qualify for a position as a nursery assistant, depending on your life experience and prior work and education history</li> <li>Learning more about how to best engage children in educational play</li> <li>Understanding more about the various developmental milestones that children should reach</li> <li>Learning how you can help the children in your care achieve their learning goals</li> </ul></CourseDescription>
        </course>

        
<course>
<title>Introduction to REBT: Rational Emotive Behaviour Therapy Certification</title>
<link>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/course/introduction-to-rebt-rational-emotive-behaviour-therapy-certification/</link>
<CourseFeaturedImage>https://staffskillstraining.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/REBT-1024x530.jpg</CourseFeaturedImage>
<location>Online</location>
<duration>2.5</duration>
<qualification>Introduction to REBT: Rational Emotive Behaviour Therapy Certification</qualification>
<CourseAccess>Lifetime</CourseAccess>
<ExamIncluded>Yes</ExamIncluded>
<compatibility> All modern browsers and devices</compatibility>
<CourseCategory>Health & Social Care</CourseCategory>
<CourseDescription><h4>Introduction to REBT: Rational Emotive Behaviour Therapy </h4> Rational Emotive Behaviour Therapy (REBT) is a talk-based therapy grounded in the principle that the way in which a person responds to events in their lives is just as important as the events themselves. REBT also emphasises the role of dysfunctional thought patterns in the maintenance of psychological distress. In this course, you will learn about the theory underpinning REBT and the techniques that REBT therapists use to help their clients lead happier lives. <h4>You Will Learn:</h4> <ul class="learn-mod"> <li>The origins of REBT</li> <li>The problems that respond well to REBT </li> <li>How REBT is delivered</li> <li>The ABC model, the framework at the heart of REBT and how it is used to help clients resolve emotional distress</li> <li>The practical interventions used by REBT therapists during and between therapy sessions</li> </ul> <h4>Benefits of Taking this Course:</h4> <ul class="learn-benefit"> <li>If you are thinking of pursuing a career as a psychotherapist, this course will provide you with a valuable introduction to an influential school of therapy</li> <li>If you wish to seek personal therapy, this course will help you decide whether REBT may be helpful for you</li> <li>If you support someone who is receiving REBT or a similar therapy, this course will help you understand how their treatment works</li> <li>If you are interested in mental health, this course will provide you with an insight into the relationship between thinking styles and wellbeing</li> </CourseDescription>
</course>